Guide to the J.D. Graham Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Financial Records (Boxes 25-30) of Series VI are arranged in "General," "Light House Establishment," and "Great Brewster Island Sea Wall Project." The first section of records, spanning 1851-1865, documents Graham's financial transactions as supervisor of the Great Lakes Harbor Improvements, and, to a lesser extent, as supervisor of the North and North West Lakes Survey. These records show equipment and staffing costs as well as outside service expenses (Boxes 25-27, folders 371-420). The finances of the lakes survey are documented in the account books (Box 27, folders 421-423) and in the following two sections. "Light House Establishment," organized chiefly by lighthouse, contains accounts of staff, equipment, and service expenses for specific lighthouses (Box 28, folders 431-46). There are also receipts for taxes paid on the salaries of the staff of the lakes survey (Box 27, folders 427-28). "Great Brewster Island Sea Wall Project" is organized by type of material and chronologically. It consists of the financial records for this single project of the survey carried out in 1864-66 (Boxes 28-30, folders 447-71).
Series VII, Personal and Family Papers (Boxes 31-40), contains personal papers of J. D. Graham and papers related to members of his immediate family. The collection contains a manuscript, "Refutation," by Graham's brother Campbell, which responds to a report by J. J. Abert (Box 31, folder 372). The document reviews Campbell Graham's military career in the Corps of Topographical Engineers. A letter by J. D. Graham's first wife, Charlotte Meade, to her cousin Miss Parker describes her happy marriage and passes on family news (folder 373).
The bulk of Series VII consists of the personal papers of J. D. Graham, which are arranged alphabetically by title. "Deeds, leases, mortgages, and other property documents" refers to goods, real estate, and land owned or rented by Graham (Box 31, folder 374-77). There is also an inventory of household furniture, dated 1857. Information on Graham's property can also be found in his insurance documents, legal papers, R. W. Meade's estate papers, and the folder on taxable property in Chicago (Box 39, folders 585-590, 591, 595). Graham's diary contains daily notes on expenses and his activities for 1854-56 (Box 31, folder 378). The financial papers (Boxes 31-38) provide the most comprehensive documentation of Graham's personal life. The papers, spanning 1847-65, consist of receipts, cancelled checks, and account books recording goods and services purchased by J. D. Graham for his family. There are notes on historical and scientific societies indicating Graham's interests (Box 39, folder 584). There is also a reproduction of a photographic portrait of Graham; the original image dates from around 1855 (Box, folder 592).
The papers contain a letter to a young James Duncan Graham Jr. from his Aunt Margaret Meade (Box 39, folder 597) and orders to Brevet Major Lawrence Pike Graham, serving in Kansas in January 1858, to escort General Calhoun, president of Kansas's Constitutional Convention, to Lecompton (folder 598). The letter containing the order alludes to the general unrest in Kansas and commands L. P. Graham to put his troops at the disposal of General Denver, Acting Territorial Governor, when he reaches Lecompton. The only other item concerning Lawrence Graham is a manuscript map of a military march from Monterey, Mexico to California in 1848-49, accompanied by a list of places with notes on the road and the availability of wood, water, and grass (Box 50, folder 827). A printed pamphlet of rules for the Lyceum Society of West Chester, Pennsylvania probably belonged to Graham's son R. W. Meade Graham (folder 599). William Montrose Graham, who attended West Point with his brother J. D., is represented by letters and supply receipts that document his military career, particularly the campaign against the Seminole Indians in Florida (Box 39, folders 600-04). Graham's son, also named William Montrose Graham, became a general in the artillery. The collection contains fourteen mounted paper print photographs of his posts at the Presido, California and Fort Riley, Kansas. The images depict officers and troops posed at the forts. There are several photographs of nineteenth century cannons.
Series VIII, Cornelius E. Clifford Papers (Box 41), contains business correspondence of Clifford, a lawyer practicing in Concord, New Hampshire. Most of the letters are from clients and colleagues concerning local civil suits in 1895-96. There are a few letters by Clifford in 1896. A speech, in Clifford's handwriting, concerns the Irish rebel Robert Emmet.
Oversize (Boxes 42-50) contains material from Series II-VII. The arrangement, based on the size of the material, parallels the order of the collection.
Surveying -- United States; Tides -- Great Lakes (North America); Canada -- Boundaries -- United States; Fort Riley (Kan.) -- Pictorial works; Great Lakes (North America) -- Maps; Great Lakes (North America) -- Surveys; Great Lakes (North America) -- Commerce; Mason-Dixon Line; Mexico -- Maps; Mexico -- Surveys; Mexico -- Boundaries -- United States; Northeast boundary of the United States -- Surveys; Presidio of San Francisco (Calif.); Southern boundary of the United States -- Surveys; Texas -- Maps; Texas -- Surveys; Texas -- Boundaries -- United States; United States -- Surveys; United States -- Boundaries -- Canada; United States -- Boundaries -- Mexico; United States -- Boundaries -- Texas; Maps -- United States; Photographs -- United States; Astronomers -- United States; Engineers -- United States; Military engineers -- United States; Surveyors -- United States; Abert, John James, 1788-1863; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887; Bartlett, John Russell, 1805-1886; Bull, John, -1851; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866; Clifford, Cornelius E.; Emory, William H. (William Hemsley), 1811-1887; Goddard, D. E.; Graham, Campbell, 1798 or 1799-1866; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865; Graham, William Montrose, 1798-1847; Graham, William Montrose, Jr., 1834-1916; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888; Gunnison, J. W. (John Williams), 1812-1853; Humphries, Andrew A.; Lee, Thomas Jefferson, 1808-1891; Long, Stephen H. (Stephen Harriman), 1784-1864; Longfellow, A. W. (Alexander Wadsworth), 1814-1901; Macomb, J. N. (John N.), 1810 or 1811-1889; Mayer, J. R. (John R.); McClellan, John, 1805-1854; Meade, George Gordon, 1815-1872; O'Donoghue, John, 1946-; Palmer, W. R. (William R.), -1862; Raynolds, W. F. (William Franklin), 1820-1894; Schroeder, F.; Thom, George; Wampler, John Morris, 1830-1863; Warren, G. K. (Gouverneur Kemble), 1830-1882; Webster, J. D. (Joseph Dana), 1811-1876; Whipple, Amiel Weeks, 1817?-1863; White, T. F.; Wickham, William F.; Graham family; United States. Army -- Artillery -- Photograph collections; United States. Army. Corps of Topographical Engineers; U.S. Lake Survey
- Correspondence, 1838-65; Series I; 3; (6 boxes) + 1 bound volume
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence contains letters to and from J. D. Graham spanning his professional and personal live. The series is arranged chronologically with Graham's letterpress copybook (copies of letters sent by Graham) for 1859-61 placed at the end.
  - Correspondence, 1838 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1839 Jul 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1844-47 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Correspondence, 1850 Jan-Jun (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Correspondence, 1850 Jul-Dec (Box 2, Folder 15-18)
  - Correspondence, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 19-30)
  - Correspondence, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 31-36)
  - Correspondence, 1853 (Box 3, Folder 37-43)
  - Correspondence, 1854 Jan-May (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1854 Jun-Dec (Box 4, Folder 45-48)
  - Correspondence, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 49-53)
  - Correspondence, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 54-59)
  - Correspondence, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 60-64)
  - Correspondence, 1858 (Box 5, Folder 65-75)
  - Correspondence, 1859 (Box 5, Folder 76-80)
    See also Letterpress copybook at the end of the Series
  - Correspondence, 1860 (Box 6, Folder 81-86)
  - Correspondence, 1861 (Box 6, Folder 87-88)
  - Correspondence, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 89-90)
  - Correspondence, 1863 Feb 3 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Correspondence, 1864 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Correspondence, 1865 (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 94-95)
  - Letterpress copybook (with index), 1859-65 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    Pages 641-52, 706-07 missing
  - Letterpress copybook: loose material found inside front cover, 1863-64, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Letterpress copybook: pages 368-75, 1860 (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - Letterpress copybook: loose material found between pages 622-23 (Box 6, Folder 99)
  - Letterpress copybook: business card found between p. 639-40 (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - Letterpress copybook: loose material found inside back cover, 1864, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 101)
- General Military Papers, 1827-68; Series II; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  General Military Papers contains documents from Graham's military career that do not belong to any one project or can not be identified with a specific project. This series is subdivided into Financial Papers, General Orders, Maps, and Other Papers, and most of the material is arranged chronologically.
  - FINANCIAL PAPERS
    - Account book, 1848-57 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - Receipts and agreements, 1833-40 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - Receipts and agreements, 1845-48 (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - Receipts and agreements, 1849-51 (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - Receipts and agreements, 1858 (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - GENERAL ORDERS
    - General orders, 1848 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    - General orders, 1852 (Box 7, Folder 108)
    - General orders, 1861 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - General orders, 1862 (Box 7, Folder 110-15)
      Accompanied by an annual index
    - General orders, 1863 Jan-Apr (Box 7, Folder 116-19)
    - General orders, 1863 May-Dec (Box 8, Folder 120-26)
    - General orders, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 127-30)
    - General orders, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - MAPS
    - Sketch of the Public Surveys in Iowa Territory, [1827-28]
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 734
    - Sketch of the Public Surveys in Wisconsin Territory, [1827-28]
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 735
    - A diagram of the triangulation for the survey of the coast of the United States ...Connecticut and Long Island, 1834
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 736
    - Map exhibiting the position of the several lines connected with the settlement of the Ohio boundary question (accompanied by 3 related maps), 1835
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 737
    - Survey of a ship canal around the falls of Niagara, ca. 1835-36
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 738
    - Map of the seat of war in east Florida, 1837
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 739
    - Map of the Cherokee cession in Alabama, 1837-38
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 740
    - Arkansas. Map of Arkansas surveying district shewing the extent of the public surveys (two versions), 1837, 1839
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 741
    - A plat exhibiting the surveys as they are in the Territory of Florida (two versions), 1837, 1839
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 742
    - Map of...various routes surveyed for the Western & Atlantic Rail Road of Georgia, 1837
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 743
    - Diagram of the state of Illinois (two versions), 1837, 1839
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 744
    - Map of the south western district Louisiana (three copies, two versions), [1837-40]
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 745
    - St. Helena district La. (two versions), [1837-40]
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 746
    - Southeastern district Louisiana (two versions), [1837-40]
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 747
    - Map of the District North of Red River La. (two versions), [1837-40]
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 748
    - Diagram of the state of Missouri (two versions), 1837, 1839
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 749
    - Core Sound North Carolina (accompanied by four related maps), 1837
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 750
    - Sketch of the public lands in the north part of Michigan, [1839-40]
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 751
    - Diagram of the surveying district South Tennessee, [1839-40]
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 752
    - Map of Texas and the countries adjacent: compiled... for the State Department (two copies each with annotations by Graham), 1844
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 753
    - Map of Texas and part of New Mexico compiled in the Bureau...chiefly for military purposes (four copies each with annotations by Graham), 1857
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 754
    - Kansas with parts of the neighboring states and territories, 1868 Oct
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 755
    - [Map of the Mississippi River from Chuteau's Island to St. Louis]
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 756
    - "Chart of the Tamasi River, surveyed and drawn by Capt. W. Cole for Col. Gates"
      See: Oversize, Box 43, folder 757
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Design of belt buckle, spurs, and decorations on the uniform, 1829-39 (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - A Report upon the Military and Hydrographical Chart of the Extremity of Cape Cod including the townships of Provincetown and Truro with their seacoasts and ship harbor
      See: Oversize, Box 42, folder 721
    - Description of the U.S. attack on Mexico City, unsigned narrative and papers dated from Mexico city, [1847-48] (Box 8, Folder 133)
    - Graham's diary from survey of Texas border, 1848 (Box 8, Folder 133.1)
    - Data on sidereal chronometer, 1848 (Box 8, Folder 134)
    - Inventory, 1848 (Box 8, Folder 135)
    - Miscellaneous astronomical and meteorological papers, 1851-59, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Annual Report of the Secretary of the Interior, to the President (reporting on the survey of public lands), 1853 Dec 9 (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Official Report to the United States Engineer Dept, of the Siege and Reduction of Fort Pulaski, Georgia, 1862 (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - Army and Navy Official Gazette, 1862-63
      See: Oversize, Box 42, folder 722
    - "Explosion of Steam Boilers," unsigned report, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - "Medicines authorized by the Med. Dept. U.S. Army extracted from the Army Regulations", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 140)
- North Eastern Boundary Survey, 1840-52; Series III; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  North Eastern Boundary Survey is subdivided into Reports, Letters, Maps; Data from Observations and Calculations; and Administrative Records. These sections are arranged chronologically.
  - REPORTS, LETTERS, MAPS
    - Draft letters and copies of correspondence, 1840-49, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 141-46)
    - Report on the survey of the Aroostook River Basin, 1841 (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - Report on the survey of St. John River and its Islands by Thomas J. Lee, [1843] (Box 9, Folder 148)
    - Sketches and notes on survey line, 1845 Aug (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - Copy of the plan for settling the boundaries accompanied by maps, 1852 Jul 30 (Box 9, Folder 150)
    - Map showing Portage Lake, Maine, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 44, folder 758
  - DATA FROM OBSERVATIONS AND CALCULATIONS
    - "Determination of the time, by observed equal altitudes of the Sun's limbs", 1840-55 (Box 9, Folder 151-55)
      See also: Oversize, Box 42, folder 723
    - Lists of latitude and longitude of various places, 1841-45, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 156)
      See also: Oversize, Box 44, folder 759
    - Miscellaneous astronomical observations and calculations, 1840-43 (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - ADMINISTRATIVE RECORDS
    - Financial papers, 1842-48 (Box 9, Folder 158-59)
    - Financial papers, 1849-51 (Box 10, Folder 160-63)
    - Inventories and other documents concerning instruments, 1843, 1849 (Box 10, Folder 164)
    - Muster rolls, 1844-52
      See: Oversize, Box 44, folder 760-68
    - Clothing accounts, 1848, 1850
      See: Oversize, Box 44, folders 769-70
    - List of North Eastern Boundary documents, 1851 Jan (Box 10, Folder 165)
- Mason-Dixon Line Survey, 1848-62; Series IV; 1.5; (4 boxes)
  Mason-Dixon Line Survey is subdivided into Reports and Maps and Copies from the Maryland and Pennsylvania Archives. These sections are arranged chronologically.
  - REPORTS AND MAPS
    - Draft report of Lieut. Col. J. Graham, U.S. Topographical Engineers, on Mason and Dixon's Line, 1850 Feb 27 (Box 11, Folder 166)
    - Report of Lieut. Col. J. D. Graham, U.S. Topographical Engineers, on Mason and Dixon's Line, 1862 (Box 11, Folder 167)
    - Maps of the Mason-Dixon line near Delaware Bay and head of the Chesapeake Bay and triangulation figure (three sketches)
      See: Oversize, Box 44, folder 771
    - Miscellaneous notes, observations, and calculations, 1848-51, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 168)
  - COPIES FROM THE MARYLAND AND PENNSYLVANIA ARCHIVES
    This subseries contains copies of documents from the original Mason-Dixon survey which Graham had made for his use. The material is arranged chronologically by the date of the originals.
    - List of documents in bundles A and B, [1849] (Box 11, Folder 169)
    - Commission from Cæcilius Lord Baltimore to Leonard Calvert for granting land, 1636 Aug 8, [1849] (Box 11, Folder 170)
    - Commission from Charles Lord Baltimore to Colonel Talbot to demand of William Penn land on the west side of the Skoolkill River, and Talbot's formal demand, 1683 Sep 17, 24, [1849] (Box 11, Folder 171)
    - Articles of agreement between Maryland and Pennsylvania touching on boundaries and commission appointing executors, 1732 May (two copies), [1849] (Box 11, Folder 172-73)
    - Commission to run the lines between Maryland and Pennsylvania, 1732 May 12, [1849] (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Testimonies regarding a land dispute in Cecil County, Maryland, 1734, [1849] (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Commission from Lt. Gov. of Pennsylvania to Lawrence Growden and Robert Peters for running temporary lines, 1738-39, [1849] (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Testimonies regarding a land dispute in Cecil County, Maryland, 1739, [1849] (Box 11, Folder 177)
    - Letters regarding relations between various colonies, the French and the Indians, 1748-49, [1849] (Box 11, Folder 178)
    - Letter from French commander at an old Shawnee village on the Ohio River to Gov. Hamilton of Pennsylvania, 1749 Aug 6 (three copies), [1849] (Box 11, Folder 179)
    - Letter from French commander at an old Shawnee village on the Ohio River, 1749 Aug 10, [1849] (Box 11, Folder 180)
    - Indenture between Lord Baltimore and Thomas and Richard Penn, 1760 Jul 4 (first of two copies), [1849] (Box 11, Folder 181)
    - Indenture between Lord Baltimore and Thomas and Richard Penn, 1760 Jul 4 (second copy), [1849] (Box 12, Folder 182)
    - Commission for running the boundary lines, 1760 Jul 5 (two copies), [1849] (Box 12, Folder 183-84)
    - Commissioner's journal, Nov 1760 - Nov 1768 (two copies), [1849] (Box 12, Folder 185-86)
    - Field notes and journal of the surveyors, Dec 1760 - Dec 1761 (two copies), [1849] (Box 13, Folder 187-88)
    - Field notes and journal of the surveyors, Nov 1763 - Oct 1767, [1849] (Box 13, Folder 189)
    - Commission to allow more time to settle the boundaries, 1764 Jun 2 (two copies), [1849] (Box 13, Folder 190-91)
    - Commission to allow more time to settle the boundaries, 1765 Dec 14 (two copies), [1849] (Box 13, Folder 192)
    - Commission to allow more time to settle the boundaries, 1766 Nov 1 (two copies), [1849] (Box 14, Folder 193-94)
    - Commission to allow more time to settle the boundaries, 1767 Nov 2 (two copies), [1849] (Box 14, Folder 195-96)
    - Memorandum regarding the settling of the stone at the middle point of the line across the peninsula, 1768 Sep 10, [1849] (Box 14, Folder 197)
    - Instructions by Mason and Dixon for determining latitude, 1769, [1849] (Box 14, Folder 198)
    - Instructions for determining latitude of Philadelphia, n.d., [1849] (Box 14, Folder 199)
    - Instructions on questions raised by the Commissioners, n.d. (two copies), [1849] (Box 14, Folder 200-01)
    - Three drafts of proposed minutes of the Commissioners' proceedings, n.d., [1849] (Box 14, Folder 202)
    - Fragment of an agreement for running the temporary lines, [1849] (Box 14, Folder 203)
    - Reasons for a superficial measure, n.d., [1869] (Box 14, Folder 204)
    - Memorandum and letter regarding the taking of an Indian baby, n.d., [1849] (Box 14, Folder 205)
- Mexican Boundary Survey, 1848-53; Series V; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Mexican Boundary Survey is subdivided into Reports, Plans, Letters, Maps; Data from Observations and Calculations; and Administrative Records. These sections are arranged chronologically.
  - REPORTS, PLANS, LETTERS, MAPS
    - Background information, instructions, reports, and notes for surveying the Mexican-American border, 1848-52, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 206-19)
    - Graham's diary, 1851 (Box 15, Folder 220)
    - Notes by Col. Abert regarding the survey, 1851 Oct 30 (Box 15, Folder 221)
    - Barometric profile of the route from San Antonio ... to the Copper Mines of Santa Rita in New Mexico, in 1851... by...Graham, accompanied by his notes
      See: Oversize, Box 44 folder 772
    - "Doctor Asa Gray's 1st Report to Lt. Col. Graham...on the Botanical Collections made...in Texas, New Mexico, and Sonora", 1851 (Box 15, Folder 222)
    - Three maps referred to in Graham's report to the Secretary of the Interior, Senate Ex. Doc. 121, 32nd Congress, 1st session, 1851
      See: Oversize, Box 44, folder 773
    - Newspaper clippings, 1852, 1855
      See: Oversize, Box 44, folder 774
    - Letter to The New York Herald by Graham in reply to J. R. Bartlett, 1853 Apr 11 (Box 15, Folder 223)
    - Notes on the various lines considered by the Mexican Boundary Commission (Box 15, Folder 224)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 225)
  - DATA FROM OBSERVATIONS AND CALCULATIONS
    - Astronomical notes, 1851, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 226)
    - Determination of longitude, 1851 (Box 15, Folder 227)
    - "Determination of the line and latitude of Indianola, Texas", 1851 Apr 25
      See: Oversize Box 44, folder 775
  - ADMINISTRATIVE RECORDS
    - Receipts, invoices, and other documents regarding equipment and personnel, 1851-53, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 228-33)
    - Returns, invoices, and other documents regarding instruments, 1850-53, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 234-40)
- Great Lakes Improvements & Lakes Survey, 1854-64; Series VI; 6; (14 boxes)
  Great Lakes Improvements & Lakes Survey is subdivided into Reports, Plans, Maps; Data from Observations and Calculations; Administrative Records; and Financial Records. The general arrangement is chronological.
  - REPORTS, PLANS, MAPS
    - Reports of Graham's Work
      - Annual reports on the work done at Racine Harbor, Manitowoc Harbor, and Milwaukee Harbor, 1854 Oct (Box 17, Folder 241)
      - Message for the President... transmitting copies of contracts, &tc., for the Improvement of harbors and rivers on Lake Michigan (H. Ex. Doc. 71 33 Cong. 1st Sess.), 1854 (Box 17, Folder 242)
      - Chart of Chicago Harbor Illinois shewing the main entrance for ships, and the state of the bar after completing the dredging..., 1854
        See: Oversize, Box 45, folder 776
      - Annual reports on the work done at Kenosha Harbor, Michigan City Harbor, and St. Joseph Harbor, 1855 Jan (Box 17, Folder 243)
      - Sketch of unknown harbor, with soundings, 1855 Sep 30
        See: Oversize, Box 46, folder 785